Guide to the Richard Pommer Papers MC.125
New York University Archives
- Series I: Papers
  - Dissertations - correspondence, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Susan Earle - correspondence with Pommer, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Frick, correspondence, lecture topics, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - IFA Library - Collection Development Committee, correspondence, memoranda, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Luebbers - article "Jean Furtrieri Prints of the Fourbes " Print Collectors' Newsletter, March - April 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Bruno Paul - correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Oral Exams, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Slides, assorted catalogs, 1978-1990 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Joseph Maria Olbrich - "Early Works and The Vienna Secession - Early Years", undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Bruegmann, Robert - "Preservation, Restoration, and Conservation", 1981 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Pop - Site/Hugh Hardy, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Princeton, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Piranesi, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Perret, notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Students, 1988-1992 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Art 370 - notes, syllabi, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Place and Dutch symposium, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Post-Modernism, 1983, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Frederick Law Olmsted, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - U.S. Post-Modernism, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Delft University - Symposium on Context and Modernity, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Rossi - notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Russia - notes, excerpts from texts, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Place - Geographic, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Henry Hobson Richardson, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Antonio Sant'Elia, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Gottfried Semper, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - James Stirling, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Kazuo Shinohara, 1971, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Skidmore, Owings and Merrill, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Alison and Peter Smithson, undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Saarinen/Roche, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Skyscraper, undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Karl Friedrich Schinkel, undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Steiner, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Soane, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Adler and Sullivan's Auditorium Theater, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Meyer Schapiro, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Paolo Soleri, undated (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - De Stijl, undated (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Spare Time, undated (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Albert Speer, undated (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Skyscraper Genre, undated (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Team 10, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Giuseppe Terragni, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Art 370 - Frank Lloyd Wright, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058546 8
  - Heinrich Tessenow, undated (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Art 370: Frank Lloyd Wright, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Frank Lloyd Wright - bibliographies, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Frank Lloyd Wright - Francisco Terrace Apartments, photos, blueprints, correspondence, 1965-1973 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Airports, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Christopher Alexander, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Der Platz der Republik/Berlin, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Frank Werner, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Berlin City Planning, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Berlin, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Berlin, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Berlin, writers, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Berliner Siedlungen, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Berlin, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Bay Area Architecture, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Aldo Van Eyck, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Theo Van Doesburg, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - American Colonial and English Vernacular Architecture, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Eugène Emmanuel Viollet-Le-Duc, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Henry Van de Velde, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Robert Venturi, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Lauretta Vinciarelli, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Robert Venturi, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Otto Wagner, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Friedrich Weinbrenner, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Werkbund Arbeit Zukunft, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Women, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - World War II, undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Broadacre City, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Early Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Art 370: Frank Lloyd Wright, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Late Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - City Plan Bibliography, undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - City Planning, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Reinhard Baumeister, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Brinckmann, undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Linear, undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Theodor Fritsch, undated (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - City Plan, undated (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - August Endell, undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Arthur Comey, undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Modern City Planning, undated (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Collins, undated (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - California, undated (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Chicago, undated (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Columbia/Reston, undated (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Environment Cities, undated (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Housing - England, undated (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Forest Hills Gardens, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Gardens/City Parks, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058547 6
  - German Housing, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - German Site Plan, 1907-1987 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Art 370, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Haussmann, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Ebenezer Howard, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - European Housing, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Werner Hegemann, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Image of City, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Jackson, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Los Angeles, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Hotels/Motels, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Mobile Homes, 1955-1979 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Mumford, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1984-1989 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Italian Museum Design - J. Perry, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Graves/Newark, 1978-1981 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - I.M. Pei/Museums, 1979-1990 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Renzo Piano and the Menil Collection, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Arata Isozaki, 1976, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Charles Moore and the Williams College of Art, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Museums, 1955-1988 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Newport, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - New Towns, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Richard Plunz, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Art 370a Modern City Planning and New York City - Bibliographies, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Grand Central, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Rockefeller Center, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - American City Planning, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Art 370a, Modern City Planning and New York City, Fall, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - New York City Zoning, 1976, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Art 370, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Art 370, undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Regional Planning, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Co-op City, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - New York City Low-Rise Housing, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Battery Park City, 1979-1989 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - SAH - New York City Architecture and Design Between the Wars Conference, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Art 370, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Thomas Bender, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Committee for the Preservation of Architectural Records, 1977-1980 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Raymond Unwin, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058548 4
  - Vienna, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Martin Wagner, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Vernacular, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Cities, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Washington D.C., 1991 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Zellenbau, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Barbara Miller Lane, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Q file, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Reyner Banham, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Alan Colquhoun, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Sigfried Giedion, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Hudnut, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Peter Meyer, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Pevsner Pioneers, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Nikolaus Pevsner, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Colin Rowe, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Debord - Spectacle, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Troubled Times, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Persico, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Gustav Platz, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Theory: Criticism and Bibliography, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Sociology - Environmental Psychology - Terminology, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Systems, Buildings, Prefabs, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Scul, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Symposium on the Politicizing of the Arts in the Western World, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Pleasure Palaces, etc., undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Perspecta, undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Theaters/Art Centers, undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Criticism 1920s, undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Functionalism, undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Parts, undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Flat Roof, undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Flat Roof - Pommer paper/presentation, undated (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Flat Roof Text/Presentation, undated (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - P. Morton Shand, undated (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Bruno Taut, undated (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Projects, undated (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Technology Structures, undated (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - David Van Zanten, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - American Architecture and the German Connection Symposium, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - American Architecture and the German Connection conference, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - American Architecture and the German Connection conference, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Chicago architecture: maps and notes, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058549 2
  - Notes on Myron Goldsmith, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Mies van der Rohe and the Political Ideology of the Modern Movement in Architecture," by Richard Pommer: draft, notes, correspondence, and articles, 1922-1986 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Notes on the politics of architecture, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Mies van der Rohe: articles and interview (photocopies), 1928-1936 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Mies van der Rohe: archival collections, 1981-1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Mies Van Der Rohe manuscripts: photocopies and notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Books owned by Mies van der Rohe: photocopies and notes, 1926, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re: "Mies van der Rohe and the Political Ideology of the Modern Movement in Architecture", 1984-1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Mies van der Rohe and American Architecture seminar, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Mies van der Rohe: articles and interviews (photocopies), 1929-1969 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Mies van der Rohe: bibliography, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Mies van der Rohe symposium, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Alois Riehl, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Luxembourg, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Alexanderplatz, 1929, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Berlin Building Expo 1931, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Tugendhat, 1931-1933, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Neue Wache, 1930-1931, 1940, undated; 1930-1931 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Afrikanische Straße apartments, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Mies and Blake oral history (photocopies), 1984, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Sergius Ruegenberg, 1969, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Brussels Exposition (photocopies), undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Brussels Exposition 1935, 1934-1935, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - "Deutsches Volk-Deutsche Arbeit", 1934, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - G Group, 1923-1924, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Mies van der Rohe and the Nazi party, 1933-1985 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Nazi archives, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Berlin Document Center, 1933-1938, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Reichsbank Competition, 1933, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Reichsbank Competition, 1933-1937 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - American Mies van der Rohe, 1940-1986 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Followers of Mies van der Rohe, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - American Mies van der Rohe: MOMA Architecture, 1934, undated (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Architectural Forum: notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Illinois Institute of Technology campus, 1944, undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - "Mies in America": notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Seagram building, 1958-1959, 1969, undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - "Mies and 'Modern Classicism,'" by Richard Pommer, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Mies van der Rohe: articles (photocopies), 1984-1990 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Barcelona Pavilion, 1929-1936, 1986-1990 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Classicism: notes and articles, 1984-1987 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - "Mies and Modern Classicism": speech given by Pommer at the University of Virginia, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics building, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - German Classicism, 1908-1922, 1972; 1908-1922 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Paul Westheim, 1913-1932, undated (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Immanuel Kant and aesthetics, 1912, 1959-1979, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Torino: articles and publications, 1917-1970, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058550 0
  - Piedmont: articles and publications, 1926, 1952-1969; 1952-1969 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Torino: articles and publications, 1932-1961 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Architecture 1750-1875, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Architecture 1750-1875: lecture notes, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Architecture 1750-1875: bibliography, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Architecture 1887-1914, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Architecture 1887-1914: lecture notes, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - History 1890-1914: notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Architecture since 1945, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Architecture since 1945, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Architecture since 1945: lecture notes, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Architecture circa 1900, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Architecture 1914-1945, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Moore and Bay Region style architecture: articles, 1939-1987 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Architecture 1900 to the Present: Problems in Historiography seminar, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - "On the Methodology of Architectural History," ed. Demetri Porphyrios; used in Architecture 1900 to the Present seminar, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Le Corbusier Seminar, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Le Corbusier Seminar, 1975, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Twentieth Century Architecture: Museum Design seminar, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Twentieth Century Architecture: Museum Design seminar, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Museum Design Seminar: Historiography, 1967-1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Museum Design Seminar: Historiography, 1951-1987, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Museum Seminar bibliography, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Architectural Theory, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058551 8
  - Kenneth Frampton, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Architectural Criticism since 1945 seminar, Spring 1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Architectural Criticism - Mumford, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Anthony Vidler, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Seminar Spring 1992, rejected, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Art 272, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Art 272, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Art 273 - 20th-Century Architecture, 1986, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Art 273 - 20th-Century Architecture, 1986, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Art 370 - Corbusier Seminar, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Art 370 - Corbusier Seminar, 1975, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Art 370 - Corbusier Seminar, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - "Recent Architecture and Mother Nature" - speech, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - "Nature in Architecture" speech at CAA, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Art 370 - Architecture and Nature in the Industrial Revolution, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Art 170 - Modern Architecture, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Columbia, Mies, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Mies Seminar, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Mies Seminar, MIT, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Projects, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Complimentary letters, 1976-1988 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Robert Bruegmann, 1982-1990 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Dennis Doordan, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Golan, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Totalitarianism, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Totalitarianism, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - History Talk, 1981-1987 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - "History Without Meaning" speech at ASCA Conference, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - SAH Commemoration Speech - "History in the Service of Architecture: Post-Modernism and Reappraisal of the Past", 1988 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - "On the Corbusian Road" - Delft University Symposium, undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - German Werkbund Conference, April 1980, undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Architecture 1914-1945, syllabus, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058552 6
  - Architecture circa 1900, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Architecture circa 1900, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Architecture 1914-45, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Architecture 1914-45, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Art 370A - Louis Kahn and His Influence, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Architecture since 1945, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Architecture since 1945, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Kahn - Dacca, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Kahn Seminar, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - 20th-Century Architecture: Museum Design Seminar *Box 17 also contains a small box of bibliographic topics and citations as well as two rolls of microfilm: Creese, Walter L. American Architecture from 1918-1933 with Special Emphasis on European Influence. Harvard University dissertation, 1949; Syracuse University, George Arents Library, assorted magazine articles, photographs and scrapbook entries., 1990 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Scope and content
    Box 17 also contains a small box of bibliographic topics and citations as well as two rolls of microfilm: Creese, Walter L. American Architecture from 1918-1933 with Special Emphasis on European Influence. Harvard University dissertation, 1949; Syracuse University, George Arents Library, assorted magazine articles, photographs and scrapbook entries.
  - Bernard Tschumi, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04655959 0
  - Bruno Taut, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - U.S., '50s and '60s - Johanson, Welse, Bellensch, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - U.S., '50s, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - American Modern, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Architecture ca. 1960, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - U.S. '20s, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - American Architectural Education, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - U.S. '40s and '50s, 1950, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - American 19th-century houses, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - American 19th-century miscellaneous, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - American '30s, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Committee for the Preservation of Architectural Records, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Previ/Lima, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Roadside Arch, 1955-1971 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Acorn Houses, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Rome, 19th and 20th centuries, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Art 370 - Roadside Architecture Seminar, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Camillo Sitte, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Columbia University Seminar on the City, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - August Sander, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Stefan Muthesius, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Raymond Loewy, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Mark Swenarton, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    General
  - Frankfurt, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04655960 8
  - Frankfurt, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - May, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - May, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - France - City Planning, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Review of "Invention de Carouge", 1968 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Heinrich Wölfflin, 1982, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Mies van der Rohe in Germany, 1909-1939, 1970-1988 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Fritz Neumeyer, 1977, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - "Mies and Modern Classicism" lecture, Graham Foundation, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Classicism: notes and articles, 1955, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "Mies and Modern Classicism" lecture: draft and notes, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 12)